JAMES CLARK

London-based | jamesmhclark@gmail.com | +447814040189

PROFILE

A Makers Coding Academy graduate, with two live freelance projects, who has been employed as an Integration Engineer for the past year. I'm a full stack software developer combining strong technical knowledge with vast training in favoured coding practices, backed by 4 years in broadcast within production/project management roles.

Technical CV: https://github.com/jmsclrk/CV

LinkedIn: https://www.linkedin.com/in/james-clark-1a6558ba

TECH SKILLS



EMPLOYMENT HISTORY

Integration Engineer at Avado

Mar 2020 - Feb 2021

- Built and deployed C# web apps that integrated Avado's systems and automated timeconsuming processes.
- Built custom APIs and integrated with numerous 3rd party APIs, developing reusable components to simplify working with external tools and services used by Avado.
- Refactored legacy code to improve performance, structure and reusability.
- Designed well-structured database objects and created complex SQL scripts to transform and cleanse data.
- Scoped tickets to a high standard, code reviewed peers' tickets providing timely feedback.
- Worked directly with stakeholders and ran projects autonomously.

LIVE PROJECTS

GymPad

https://apps.apple.com/gb/app/gympad/id1505074064

- React Native / Django REST Framework / Docker.
- Gym tracking notes app.
- Well thought out object relationships.
- Customizable interface with dark mode and themes.
- Offline management and version control allowing seamless use online, offline and across numerous devices.
- Currently only released to iOS but has been built Android ready.
- Demo video: https://youtu.be/LDuSeBwlloE
- Developing frontend web interface for interacting with same app data (TypeScript / React).



Amma Hackney

www.ammahackney.co.uk

- React / Django REST Framework.
- Website for a new food business offering monthly supper clubs delivered, based in Hackney, London.
- Responsive layout snaps between one and two panels depending on screen width, with a mobile-first design.
- Order form POSTs to Django backend, submits order to Google Forms before emailing confirmation via the Gmail API.
- Admin area to manage menu, order dates and instructions.
- Worked closely with the stakeholder to build and agree on functionality and an aesthetic that worked for them.



Sep – Dec 2019 2011 – 2014

EDUCATION

Makers Academy Coding Bootcamp University of Bristol Biological Sciences (2:1)

EXTRACURRICULAR

- Member of Sky's mentor scheme, welcoming and guiding new employees.
- Dedicated gym-goer and runner who often takes part in organised charity events, successfully sticking to a full fitness routine around a busy work schedule.

FURTHER EMPLOYMENT HISTORY

Production Manager / Coordinator at Sky Sports, Sky UK

Nov 2017 - Jul 2019

- End-to-end supervision of the complete production process for golf sporting events covered by Sky Sports, working closely with the Head of Golf to accommodate for up to four golf tournaments per week.
- Planning all logistical, financial and technological aspects of production.
- Managing diverse production teams in Europe and the United States with crew numbers ranging from 20 to 250 people depending on the tier of production.
- Testing the latest technologies, such as virtual reality, and adapting them to Sky's sports coverage to enhance the viewer experience.
- Effectively managing the deadlines and expectations of overlapping production events of different scales and priorities, to ensure all events run smoothly.
- Co-planned and managed the 2018 Ryder Cup and The Open, Sky Sports' two biggest broadcast events (250+ crew members, £1.5m+ budgets).

Production Coordinator at BBC

May 2016 - Nov 2017

- Developed close relationships with all departments and external contract providers.
- Countered unexpected problems during production with both instant and longer-term solutions to resume filming immediately and prevent recurrence.
- Recruited and effectively managed crew.

Development Researcher at Hungry Bear Media

May 2015 - May 2016

- Ensured the efficient running of the office by centrally supporting all ongoing productions.
- Produced, filmed and edited taster reels for new ideas.
- Managed the diaries of three busy executives and the development team.